stop paying for expensive tools like mid
journey and doll e for image creation I
found a brilliant free alternative for
you tensor art
AI it allows you to choose from
different models to achieve various
Artistic Styles from photorealistic to
anime it also has built in character
consistency allowing you to generate a
particular character in different poses
and backgrounds so you can use the
images to create a story or as a
narrator character for your videos as
for the features and how to use it I am
going to cover it all and share a sample
I generated using prompt generated by
chat GPT let's begin with the tutorial
open tensor doai and sigen to generate
100 free images daily and run and remix
their pre-existing Community prompts
online once you sign up notice the
several tabs available in a vertical
Arrangement on the left hand side you
can go through those there are AI tools
available to check out and generated
models are available in the models tab
the library is vast to explore it also
has some events going on as well as a
leaderboard so it feels more like a
community driven by creators well moving
forward let's try generating an image as
for the prompt I asked chat GPT to write
me a well structured prompt for a boy
skating this is the prompt I will be
using a young Asian boy around 12 years
old with short black hair and bright
green eyes is midair doing a kickflip on
his skateboard he's wearing a red helmet
a blue graphic t-shirt ripped jeans and
black sneakers he's in a concrete skate
park with graffiti murals on the walls
in the background the afternoon sun is
casting Long Shadows and the sky is a
clear blue with a few fluffy white
clouds it is good to be detailed with
your prompt and try covering all aspects
of the image going from character
features to character pose and the
weather and background ground so I now
just click the blue colored create
button it took me to a page where I will
be mentioning all the details first
there was the prompt column which I
filled with the chat GPT prompt I
created then there was the negative
prompt colum where you basically fill in
what you do not want you can also write
about errors AI can make like I wrote
extra limbs and bad
proportions then it has options
available regarding the models which I
skipped for now though they can be
useful as there was an option to add low
R which basically is for specialized
model specifications and style so you
can be particular about your desires you
may also add control net which uses a
reference image to create more accurate
results it is well worth using if you
have good references available which are
clear and of high quality you can also
add embeddings there is the option of
vae which you can EXP experiment with
and see how it produces different color
performance of the image I let it be at
automatic for my testing then you select
the aspect ratio which I set as portrait
you can also opt for landscape or Square
or a custom size there is an option to
fill in for the sampling method which
will yield different results for the
same prompt this is because different
options will have different approaches
to refining images from the prompt you
can experiment with it the sampling
steps option basically is for the number
of steps AI uses to refine your prompt
image generation however note that
higher sampling steps burn through
credits faster there is the CFG scale
that you set which refers to how much
you want your generated image to adhere
to The Prompt I let it be at seven then
there is the seed column which will
generate you the same image for the same
number you input given that all all
other parameters are the same you can
put this to use if you have generated a
good clear image you can turn on upscale
to generate higher detailed image you
can use layer diffusion to generate
transparent background image and the a
detailer reduces face collapse and hand
deformities in generated image again
credits are used the higher the quality
you go for there are even more advanced
settings which you can opt to dig in
once you get a grasp of the the other
settings I realize it all sounds very
technical but having so many features is
a big plus just don't get overwhelmed
and have fun
experimenting okay so now that the
details have been filled you click on
generate it takes a few seconds though
it can be minutes depending on the
prompt and other input parameters in
terms of generation speed it would be
somewhere around a three out of five in
my case my prompt was fairly simple Le
and it generated the image fast let me
go about the image it generated first of
all the quality was great even though I
did not upscale it it was a clear image
also the detailing and the realism as
you may say were impressive I believe
this AI tool can surely be used for
Content creation the image produced was
bright and fairly relevant to my prompt
I also wanted to check about character
consistency so I slightly changed my
prompt and generated it again this time
I only asked for the character to be
doing a cartwheel instead of
skateboarding I know this posture is
much more complex but that's why I gave
this prompt the image it generated was
still good though with errors I expected
first of all the limbs were deformed
secondly there was disproportion in
terms of length of Limbs still the
character consistency was clearly there
this can be put to various uses like
creating Story videos Etc so to give
give an opinion from an AI enthusiast's
perspective I will rate the image
generation of tensor AI to be 4.2 out of
5 it is seriously impressive being a
free software I can even compare it to
paid AI tools now before we wrap this up
I have some useful tips for you try
setting sampling method to DPM plus plus
2 m caras IMO it is overall great for a
general choice you can set the sampling
steps to 30 it is a good good midpoint
as it also does not burn much credits
you can avoid very complex poses like
the cartwheel prompt I gave though I am
not saying tensor won't be able to
generate it it is still tough for AI
image generators to be highly accurate
with them you can try selecting the
model coloring page diffusion it is
great for creating high quality coloring
pages which can be used on platforms
like Etsy one thing to note is sometimes
tensor art can take ages to generate an
image so if you're stuck like that you
can also try another alternative called
cart. well that's it for today guys if
you found the video useful do subscribe
for more such useful AI tutorials cheers